<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>YouTube on Fgutep.xyz</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/youtube/</link>
        <description>Recent content in YouTube on Fgutep.xyz</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Felipe Gutiérrez A</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/youtube/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>YouTube</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/yt/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/yt/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;youtube&#34;&gt;YouTube
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I own and produce content in two YouTube channels. Both started during the 2024 summer break  and I try to upload to them every time it&amp;rsquo;s possible for me. It&amp;rsquo;s worth noting that while both of these Channels are Spanish-speaking this information is published originally in English as it&amp;rsquo;s a more accessible language for business demographics (while the channels are focused on the common individual or student that speaks Spanish natively).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fguteping&#34;&gt;Fguteping
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A channel dedicated to my own projects, small and large. I try to post every time I make a passion project, or to update on larger developments. For now, it&amp;rsquo;s a pretty small channel, I have yet to edit and upload more videos, it&amp;rsquo;s obviously time consuming to record, edit and publish minimum viable videos to it, but I do every time I get the chance.  I think having this is cool, not only to share my things to the world (although I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to upload to YouTube since I first found out about it) but to also keep a repository to my more tangible projects, to everything that can&amp;rsquo;t be accurately stored in GitHub such as the emotions that can be conveyed through voice and video, and the sound of filing a misfit on a design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I try to keep it mostly medium to high quality in terms of cleanliness and how polished it&amp;rsquo;s videos are, I do not intend to restrict myself to upload something if I don&amp;rsquo;t have the time to do so. Sometimes we make cool stuff in classes, or in projects, and with the due dates to these nearing every time more closely I want to document and share it anyway, without having to stress about multiple hours of editing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I share this as I want you to understand the spirit in which I make these videos. That being said take a look (here)[https://www.youtube.com]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;repasopaso&#34;&gt;RepasoPaso
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is my Spanish teaching YouTube channel. The topics I teach are topics that I considered myself (and often proved) having a good grasp of. While I do not intend to cover as many topics as possible, nor to cover full Syllabus of classes or learning series (For that I would recommend other YouTube channels such as &amp;ldquo;The Organic Chemistry Teacher&amp;rdquo; that covers a variety of different programs in full depth). I do intend to cover topics that are &lt;em&gt;tricky&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;often over-complicated in their explanation&lt;/em&gt;. This is a channel for the average-Joe of a CS/EE Engineering Student, the topics I cover I cover in a quick, easy to understand and very visual way. I teach these topics as I &lt;em&gt;would&amp;rsquo;ve wanted&lt;/em&gt; for these to be taught to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of presentation I&amp;rsquo;ve made up my mind on this channel: I prefer Quantity over prettiness. While I must and will continue to guarantee that my videos are useful, well taught, with decent audio and video quality and (mathematically or semantically) correct; I will post a video that falls out of the norm or style if that means it can help. I will have videos with a virtual blackboard, with me on a classroom on a whiteboard, with my hands on paper, on a multimeter. I want to get it out there if I can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spirit of this particular channel is to show that some topics that are often complicated to grasp at the start or that seem incredibly dense by the way they are taught can be actually be understood and used in an utilitarian, effective manner. And for topics that are not that complicated, but that are current or foundational to other areas of engineering it seeks to provide a fresh, fast and straight to the point perspective in them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to take a look, or learn something new, (please feel free to check out RepasoPaso.)[https://www.youtube.com/@RepasoPaso]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-channels&#34;&gt;Other Channels:
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I participate in other channels publishing videos there as well, such as the training video series for Fusion 360 mechanical and part design over at (RAS Uniandes YouTube channel)[https://www.youtube.com/@RasUniandes]. While these are minor appearances they can be really useful for someone looking to learn a quick topic in a pinch or for training people within these organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
